<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>davidhwang.me</title><link href="https://davidhwang.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://davidhwang.me/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://davidhwang.me/</id><updated>2021-09-26T11:59:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Wine Balderdash</title><link href="https://davidhwang.me/wine-balderdash.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-26T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-26T11:59:00-07:00</updated><author><name>David Hwang</name></author><id>tag:davidhwang.me,2021-09-26:/wine-balderdash.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The rules for a variant of Balderdash played with wines instead of words.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wine Balderdash is a variant of the game Balderdash where instead of words and their definitions, the game is played with wines and their labeled descriptions. I've only played it once, but it was a great amount of fun. It's a game that combines creativity and comical moments, especially as the rounds progress and wine is drunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials: wines, pens, sticky notes &amp;amp; tape, and scraps of paper. Preferably, each player brings their own wine, selecting for wine with an ornate/outrageous/comical description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setup: each player writes down the description of the bottle on a piece of paper. The bottle's description should then be covered up with tape and/or sticky-notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to play: Wine Balderdash is played in rounds. During each round, one player serves as the leader. To start the round, the leader serves the wine that they brought to each of the players. Players then taste served wine. Next, players privately write down plausible sounding descriptions of the wine on a scrap of paper and place that scrap into a hat. The leader of the round also places the actual description into the hat. Then, the leader reads each description from the hat out loud, and each player guesses which description was the actual description. One point is awarded to each player who guesses the actual description. Points are also awarded to players whose descriptions are guessed by other players, one point for each guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it! That's the whole game. On a personal note: I co-invented this game with my spouse for an event held at my cooperative house, drawing inspriation from Jony Ive's voiceovers for Apple products.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Capturing Ideas While Out And About</title><link href="https://davidhwang.me/capturing-ideas-while-out-and-about.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-26T11:59:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-26T11:59:00-07:00</updated><author><name>David Hwang</name></author><id>tag:davidhwang.me,2020-04-26:/capturing-ideas-while-out-and-about.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Using a pocket notebook instead of a phone to capture ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/my_pocket_notebook.png" alt="Wallet and pocket notebook combined into two object"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;

&lt;label for="mn-img-my-pocket-notebook" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;input type="checkbox" id="mn-img-my-pocket-notebook" class="margin-toggle"/&gt;
&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;
  My personal notebook + wallet combo. About the size of a smartphone. I bought it here: &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07KGMDJQJ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o06_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1"&gt;Amazon link&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to a process described by Andy Matuschak&lt;label for="sn-andy-notepad" class="margin-toggle sidenote-number"&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="sn-andy-notepad" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&lt;span class="sidenote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://notes.andymatuschak.org/z5FKgZAnMhS73t9kenbVUYx23CHSQAE1gKxVf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pocket memo pad to capture into writing inbox while out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, I carry a pocket notebook when I'm out and about to capture ideas, which later get transfered out and expanded upon. I used to use a phone to capture these transient thoughts, but switched to a notebook for two reasons: social misunderstandings &amp;amp; inefficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social misunderstandings occurred when others mistook my phone-based note taking for disinterest or distraction. This got bothersome enough that I started explaining why I was taking out my phone, but doing that awkwardly interrupted the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inefficiency came when trying to compose text and &lt;em&gt;diagrams&lt;/em&gt;. Using a phone for diagramming has always felt encumbered and slow. Inefficiency also came through distraction by the notifications that I would see while capturing a thought. Even worse, after taking out my phone, it continued as a peripheral distraction by just being "out".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I've been generally happy with my pocket notebook, I've looked into a couple alternatives in the past couple months. I've toyed with carrying around an iPad &amp;amp; stylus instead, but remain against it. I don't want to add another thing that I need to carry. Also, I think the aforementioned social misunderstandings would still occur. In a similar vein, I did a short search for an "auto-transcribe-to-the-cloud" smart pen, which ideally would speed up the time for transferring writings out of my pocket notebook. I found the Neo Smartpen&lt;label for="sn-neo-smartpen" class="margin-toggle sidenote-number"&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="checkbox" id="sn-neo-smartpen" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&lt;span class="sidenote"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.neosmartpen.com/en/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neo Smartpen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It requires you to use a specialized paper, but they provide relatively affordable notebooks and print-your-own PDFs for their speicalized paper.&lt;/span&gt;, but haven't yet felt that transcription is too toilsome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few parting thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For those that want to continue to use their phones for capturing transient thoughts, I recommend enabling Notes to be directly accessible from the lock screen. This reduces the friction to start writing and reduces the chance of getting distracted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have only started using my notebook since Winter, so I haven't felt the annoyance of taking a bulkier wallet with me around with me during the Summer when I'm wearing fewer jackets and more shorts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>